Mathias Thor - Curriculum Vitae

Danish • Born March 21 - 1993 • GSM +45 2918 4320 • Web mathiasthor.github.io • Mail mathias thor@hotmail.com

Summery

Mathias Thor is currently pursuing a PhD degree with SDU Embodied Systems for Robotics and Learning at the University of Southern Denmark. The primary aim of his research is to develop adaptive locomotion controllers that are able to recognize and adapt to different robot bodies and environments. Although in his early years of conducting research, Mathias has already won several awards, been granted the EliteForsk travel grant, and published many scientific papers on artificial intelligence and robotics.



Education

2017 - 2021 4+4 Ph.D., University Of Southern Denmark [mathias@mmmi.sdu.dk]

Address: Odense, Denmark

Project title: Neurorobotic Technology for Advanced Robot Motor Control

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Poramate Manoonpong

2019 (Oct.) Visiting Researcher, Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology

Address: Rayong, Thailand

Institute: Bio-Inspired Robotics & Neural Engineering (BRAIN-LAB) Collaborator: Dr. Theerawit Wilaiprasitporn & Dr. Nat Dilokthanakul

2019 Visiting Researcher, Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics

(July-Sept.) Address: Nanjing, China

Institute: Bio-inspired Structure and Surface Engineering (IBSS)

Collaborator: Prof. Zhang Zhuo

2016 - 2019 Master of Science in Robotics, University Of Southern Denmark

Danish weighted average master grade average of 12.0 (w/o mater thesis)

Project title: Modular Legged-Robotic System Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Poramate Manoonpong

Master thesis grade: 12

2013 - 2016 Bachelor of Science in Robotics, University Of Southern Denmark

Danish weighted average bachelor grade average of 10.9 (w/o bachelor thesis)

Project title: Embodied control of a dung beetle inspired hexapod

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Poramate Manoonpong

Bachelor thesis grade: 12

Experience

- 2019 Guest talk on Robotics, Neural Control and Reinforcement Learning BRAIN-LAB Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology, Thailand
- Teaching "Adaptive embodied locomotion control systems"9-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Teaching "Adaptive embodied locomotion control systems" 9-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark

2018 Teaching the course "Underactuated Robotics"
6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark

2017 - 2018 Teaching assistant on the course "Mathematical methods in programming"
1-semester Physics and Technology, University of Southern Denmark

2015 - 2017 Part-time programmer at Universal Robots
Odense, Denmark

Supervision

Master Students

- 2019 2020 Jens Troels Nielsen "Compliance controller for a legged robot system" 40 ECTS 10-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2019 2020 Christian Quist Nielsen "Legged robot locomotion control using proprioceptive sensory feedback" 40 ECTS 10-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
 - 2018 Florentijn Degroote "Neural control of a compliant gummi arm robot"
 20 ECTS 10-semester Robot Systems, KU Leuven / University of Southern Denmark
 Co-supervisor
 - 2018 Salman Taj "Modeling, Simulation, and Control of a Millipede Inspired Robot" 30 ECTS - 10-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark Co-supervisor

Bachelor Students

- 2019 Bjarke Larsen "Adaptive gait generation for a hexapod robot in unstructured environments" 15 ECTS 6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Jeppe Langaa "Modeling, Simulation, and Control of a pipe inspection robot" 15 ECTS 6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Jens Troels Nielsen "Modeling, Simulation, and Control of a pipe inspection robot" 15 ECTS - 6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark

Conference contributions

- 2019 Presenting a paper at the iROS 2019 conference The Venetian, Macau
- 2018 Media Operation and Session Chair at the IYCBE 2018 conference University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Presenting a paper at the IYCBE 2018 conference University of Southern Denmark
- 2017 Presenting a paper at the SWARM 2017 conference Kyoto University, Japan

Publication list

2020

IJ4) Generic Neural Locomotion Control Framework for Legged Robots

M. Thor, T. Kulvicius, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems 2020 (Journal paper - under review)

2019

IJ3: A Fast Online Frequency Adaptation Mechanism for CPG-Based Robot Motion Control

M. Thor, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters 2019 (Journal paper)

DOI: 10.1109/LRA.2019.2926660

IJ2: Error-Based Learning Mechanism for Fast Online Adaptation in Robot Motor Control

M. Thor, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems 2019 (Journal paper)

DOI: 10.1109/TNNLS.2019.2927737

IC6: CPG Driven RBF Network Control with Reinforcement Learning for Gait Optimization of a Dung Beetle-Like Robot

Matheshwaran Pitchai, Xiaofeng Xiong, <u>Mathias Thor</u>, Peter Billeschou, Peter Lukas Mailänder, Binggwong Leung, Tomas Kulvicius, and Poramate Manoonpong

In Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2019 (Conference paper)

DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-30487-4_53

IC5: Modular Neural Control for Dung Beetle-like Leg Movements of a Dung Beetle-like Robot

Binggwong Leung, Mathias Thor, and Poramate Manoonpong

In the 9th International Symposium on Adaptive Motion of Animals and Machines (Conference paper)

DOI: 10.5075/epfl-BIOROB-AMAM2019-12

2018

IC4: MORF - Modular Robot Framework (Best Student Paper Award)

Mathias Thor, Jørgen Christian Larsen, and Poramate Manoonpong

In The 2nd International Youth Conference of Bionic Engineering - IYCBE2018 (Conference abstract)

ISBN: 978-2-88945-585-0

${\tt IJ1:}$ A dung beetle-inspired robotic model and its distributed sensor-driven control for walking and ball rolling

M. Thor, T. Strøm-Hansen, L. B. Larsen, A. Kovalev, S. N. Gorb, E. Baird, and P. Manoonpong

Artificial Life and Robotics 2018 (Journal paper)

DOI: 10.1007/s10015-018-0456-8

IC3: Modular neural control for bio-inspired walking and ball rolling of a dung beetle-like robot

Binggwong Leung, Mathias Thor, and Poramate Manoonpong

In ALife 2018 (Conference paper)

DOI: 10.1162/isal_a_00064

2017

IC2: Advantages of using a biologically plausible embodied kinematic model for enhancement of speed and multifunctionality of a walking robot (Best Student Paper Award)

Mathias Thor, Theis Strøm-Hansen, and Leon Bonde Larsen

In Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Swarm Behavior and Bio-Inspired Robotics - SWARM2017 (Conference paper)

IC1: Distributed Sensor-Driven Control for Bio-Inspired Walking and Ball Rolling of a Dung Beetle-Like Robot

Theis Strøm-Hansen, <u>Mathias Thor</u>, Leon Bonde Larsen, Emily Baird, and Poramate Manoonpong In Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Swarm Behavior and Bio-Inspired Robotics - SWARM2017 (Conference paper)

Fundings

EliteForsk-Travel Grant 2019

Funding Agency: Ministry of Education and Research (Copenhagen)

Amount: DKK 200.000
Grant period: 2019-01 to 2020-12

Foundation Idella Study Travel Grant 2018

Funding Agency: Ministry of Education and Research (Copenhagen)

Amount: DKK 20.000

Grant period: 2018-08 to 2019-06

International partners

Prof. Zhendong Dai: Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, China. Collaboration on robot control and bio-inspired movement.

Prof. Stanislav Gorb: Kiel University, Germany. Collaboration on the modelling of insects and their movement.

Prof. Emily Baird: Lund University, Sweden. Collaboration on the modelling of insects and their movement.

Dr. Theerawit Wilaiprasitporn & Dr. Nat Dilokthanakul: Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology, Thailand. Collaboration neural control.